Big cops. Small town. Moderate violence.
Hot Fuzz is a crime, action, comedy film directed by Edgar Wright.
Former London constable Nicholas Angel finds it difficult to adapt to his
new assignment in the sleepy British village of Sandford.
Not only does he miss the excitement of the big city, but he
also has a well-meaning oaf for a partner.
However, when a series of grisly accidents rocks Sandford, Angel
smells something rotten in the idyllic village.
Nicholas Angel, played by Simon Pegg.
PC Danny Butterman, played by Nick Frost.
Inspector Frank Butterman, played by Jim Broadbent.
DS Andy Wainwright, played by Paddy Considine.
DC Andy Cartwright, played by Rafe Spall.
Sergeant Tony Fisher, played by Kevin Eldon.
Hot Fuzz is a 2007 British buddy cop action comedy film directed by
Edgar Wright, who co-wrote the film with Simon Pegg.
Pegg stars as Nicholas Angel, an elite London police officer, whose proficiency makes the rest of his team look bad,
causing him to be re-assigned to a West Country village where a series of gruesome deaths takes place.
Nick Frost stars alongside him as Police Constable
Danny Butterman, Angel's partner.
Hot Fuzz is the second and most commercially successful film in the Three Flavours
Cornetto trilogy, following Shaun of the Dead and followed by The World's End.
Over 100 action films were used as inspiration for the script.
Principal photography took place in Wells, Somerset, for eleven weeks and ten artists
worked on VFX, which involved explosions, gory gunfire scenes and a flip book.
Released on 16 February 2007 in the United Kingdom and 20 April in the United States, Hot Fuzz received
acclaim from critics and grossed US$80 million worldwide on a budget of $12–16 million.
In 2020, Empire named it the 67th-greatest film of the 21st century.
The film explores themes of countryside, police, village, arrest, parody.
The tone is lighthearted.